<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agile on LAURENT PARENTEAU</title>
    <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agile on LAURENT PARENTEAU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:48:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/agile/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Escaping the Valley of Death: Gradient Descent Strategies for Startup Survival</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/escaping-the-valley-of-death-gradient-descent-strategies-for-startup-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:48:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/escaping-the-valley-of-death-gradient-descent-strategies-for-startup-survival/</guid>
      <description>In machine learning (core to neural network, AI, and LLM), gradient descent is a robust optimization algorithm used to find the minimum of a function. It works by iteratively stepping toward the steepest descent, gradually honing in on the optimal solution.
In the startup world, founders embark on a journey to find product/market fit (PMF)—that magical inflection point where their product perfectly satisfies a strong market demand. This process often involves continuous iteration, pivoting when necessary, and refining their offering based on market feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Product-Market Fit</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-product-market-fit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-product-market-fit/</guid>
      <description>In tech startups, achieving product-market fit (PMF) is often the difference between success and failure. This comprehensive guide will walk you through the essentials of PMF: what it is, how to recognize it, strategies for achieving it, and why it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to prioritize it over technical improvements. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Recognizing Product-Market Fit Product-market fit, a term coined by Andy Rachleff, occurs when you have a unique product offering that people desperately want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Startup Prioritization Playbook: A Simple Framework for Maximum Impact</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-startup-prioritization-playbook-a-simple-framework-for-maximum-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-startup-prioritization-playbook-a-simple-framework-for-maximum-impact/</guid>
      <description>Time flies, competition moves, and money runs out. This environment is the harsh reality that every startup confronts. With countless tasks to accomplish and limited resources, startups are perpetually in a race against time. The question is not whether you can do everything—you can&amp;rsquo;t—but how do you decide what to do first?
The art of prioritization is crucial for startup success, yet it must be more widely recognized and done appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplification: The Key to Scaling Engineering in Fast-Growing Startups</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:49:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</guid>
      <description>In startups, rapid growth is the holy grail. Founders dream of the day their company takes off, experiencing exponential user growth, revenue, and market share. However, this dream scenario comes with its own set of challenges, particularly for engineering teams. Recently, I had an enlightening conversation with the head of engineering at a young startup experiencing this very situation. Their story is a valuable lesson for engineering leaders facing similar challenges in fast-growing environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Best Standup Setup for Your Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The Problem
We were working on a critical project, with a huge emphasis put on delivering on time. I realized that the critical nature combined with the time bound constraint was causing some stress for the team. The team needed to be focus on the goals we had instead of worried about possible outcomes and other conjectures. I knew that if the stress wasn’t relieved, we wouldn’t be able to succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fixed Sprint Duration</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/beyond-fixed-sprints-duration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 19:06:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/beyond-fixed-sprints-duration/</guid>
      <description>Everything starts for good reasons. When you start a new project, getting a cadence, a sense of progress, a way to see the journey done so far and what lies ahead provide benefits. But has you progress, it is time to revisit this cadence.
 Choosing a sprint length at the start of each sprint is a waste of energy. Experiment with a couple of lengths, make a decision, and stick with it until there is a significant reason to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
