<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plato on Laurent Parenteau</title>
    <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/plato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plato on Laurent Parenteau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 06:17:33 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/plato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Simplicity: Why Complex Solutions Aren&#39;t Always Better</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 06:17:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</guid>
      <description>In the world of software engineering, complexity often takes center stage. We celebrate intricate algorithms, sprawling architectures, and convoluted code as signs of expertise. But what if I told you that complexity isn&amp;rsquo;t always the answer? In fact, more often than not, simpler solutions are not only easier to understand and maintain but also more effective in solving real-world problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand why complexity is alluring. Complex code and systems can make us feel like we&amp;rsquo;re tackling profound problems, and they can impress colleagues and peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Initial Engineering Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-your-initial-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-your-initial-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>The Problem
When I joined an early stage startup as the first engineer, one of my goals was to build out the initial engineering team we needed. Building that initial engineering team is really critical and it must be done right. Having an initial team that is great (or bad) will have a huge impact on the startup as a whole. So I had to be sure I was building the right team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Best Standup Setup for Your Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The Problem
We were working on a critical project, with a huge emphasis put on delivering on time. I realized that the critical nature combined with the time bound constraint was causing some stress for the team. The team needed to be focus on the goals we had instead of worried about possible outcomes and other conjectures. I knew that if the stress wasn’t relieved, we wouldn’t be able to succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
