<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>strategy on LAURENT PARENTEAU</title>
    <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in strategy on LAURENT PARENTEAU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:49:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/strategy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplification: The Key to Scaling Engineering in Fast-Growing Startups</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:49:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</guid>
      <description>In startups, rapid growth is the holy grail. Founders dream of the day their company takes off, experiencing exponential user growth, revenue, and market share. However, this dream scenario comes with its own set of challenges, particularly for engineering teams. Recently, I had an enlightening conversation with the head of engineering at a young startup experiencing this very situation. Their story is a valuable lesson for engineering leaders facing similar challenges in fast-growing environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crucial Role of Strategy for Engineering Leaders</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-crucial-role-of-strategy-for-engineering-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 15:38:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-crucial-role-of-strategy-for-engineering-leaders/</guid>
      <description>In the fast-paced world of technology and innovation, engineering leaders often navigate complex challenges and make critical decisions that impact their teams, projects, and organizations. While strategy is commonly associated with business executives, it&amp;rsquo;s equally crucial for engineering leaders to grasp and apply strategic thinking within their domain. Understanding strategy and its application can significantly enhance your effectiveness in navigating the complexities of your role and driving success for your organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Growth: Myth, Reality, and Strategic Considerations</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:37:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard the Indian story of the man who asked for his reward to be 1 grain of wheat placed on the 1st square of a chessboard and doubling the number of grains on each subsequent square. While there are only 64 squares, you&amp;rsquo;d need 2,000 times the world&amp;rsquo;s wheat production to provide that reward. This famous story shows our lack of intuition about exponential growth and its power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
