<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Laurent Parenteau</title>
    <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Laurent Parenteau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:37:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Growth: Myth, Reality, and Strategic Considerations</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:37:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</guid>
      <description>While exponential growth demonstrates immense potential, it is crucial to realistically assess growth rates, sustainability, and timeframes to avoid overestimating outcomes and sometimes consider high-risk strategies instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tragic Tale of King Han: The Consequences of Ignored Counsel</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-tragic-tale-of-king-han-the-consequences-of-ignored-counsel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:06:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-tragic-tale-of-king-han-the-consequences-of-ignored-counsel/</guid>
      <description>In the kingdom of Wisdom Peak, King Han&amp;rsquo;s tragic tale illustrates the perils of ignoring wise counsel and succumbing to the allure of shortcuts, emphasizing the importance for leaders to trust their own judgment and balance risk-taking with prudence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Success and Failure: A Rational Approach</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/decoding-success-and-failure-a-rational-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 07:08:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/decoding-success-and-failure-a-rational-approach/</guid>
      <description>In software engineering, recognizing the roles of both skill and luck through probabilistic thinking, as proposed by Annie Duke, can lead to better decision-making and constructive self-reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the Grey: A Probabilistic Approach to Engineering Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/embracing-the-grey-a-probabilistic-approach-to-engineering-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 07:10:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/embracing-the-grey-a-probabilistic-approach-to-engineering-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>Adopting Annie Duke&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;thinking in bets&amp;rsquo; framework in software engineering emphasizes making decisions based on a probabilistic perspective, acknowledging the roles of skill and luck, and fostering a continuous improvement mindset to navigate the inherent uncertainties of the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Simplicity: Why Complex Solutions Aren&#39;t Always Better</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:17:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</guid>
      <description>In software engineering complexity is often celebrated for tackling profound challenges, but simpler solutions are generally easier to maintain, understand, and often more effective in real-world applications,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking the Right Tool for a Remote Engineering Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/picking-the-right-tool-for-a-remote-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 20:34:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/picking-the-right-tool-for-a-remote-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>How to pick the right project management tools by trials and gathering feedback, highlighting the value of adaptive learning and experimentation in process improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cohesive Distributed Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-a-cohesive-distributed-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 16:15:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-a-cohesive-distributed-team/</guid>
      <description>To build a cohesive distributed team across multiple time zones, prioritize effective communication rooted in trust, empathy, and a shared understanding of the mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Remote Workers in Remote-Unfriendly Environments</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/tips-for-remote-workers-in-remote-unfriendly-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/tips-for-remote-workers-in-remote-unfriendly-environments/</guid>
      <description>7 essential tips for success as a remote worker in a non-remote-friendly environment, emphasizing proactive communication, overcoming biases, and maintaining productivity to thrive amidst potential challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Tool Box for Remote Startups</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/minimal-tool-box-for-remote-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/minimal-tool-box-for-remote-startups/</guid>
      <description>The only three communication tools that are crucial for remote startups to establish clarity, team cohesion, and productivity from the outset, advocating for starting with minimal tools and adjusting as the team grows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Work Problems Aren’t Related to Remote at All</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/remote-work-problems-arent-related-to-remote-at-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/remote-work-problems-arent-related-to-remote-at-all/</guid>
      <description>Problems attributed to remote work are often present in office settings as well, cautioning against mistaking symptoms for underlying issues and emphasizing the need to address root causes effectively in both environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Initial Engineering Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-your-initial-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/building-your-initial-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>How I successfully built a strong initial team by prioritizing cultural fit alongside technical skills, ensuring the team could effectively navigate early challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel gathering from the interview process</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/intel-gathering-from-the-interview-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/intel-gathering-from-the-interview-process/</guid>
      <description>While job interviews help employers evaluate candidates, they also allow candidates to assess the company&amp;rsquo;s openness, reliability, and priorities by observing the interview process and the balance of technical, soft skill, and product-oriented questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lessons from Parenting</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/leadership-lessons-from-parenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/leadership-lessons-from-parenting/</guid>
      <description>Lessons learned from interacting with children, such as keeping promises, encouraging decision-making, explaining reasoning, listening actively, understanding motivations, and setting positive examples, are directly applicable to effective leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Best Standup Setup for Your Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/finding-the-best-standup-setup-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>To address team stress on a time-critical project, we aligned on goals, reduced meeting frequency, implemented virtual standups, and continuously adjusted our approach based on team feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fixed Sprint Duration</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/beyond-fixed-sprints-duration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 19:06:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/beyond-fixed-sprints-duration/</guid>
      <description>Fixed sprint durations may initially help maintain progress, but teams should consider flexible, natural rhythms and explore alternatives like Kanban to improve productivity and better align with varying task requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Valuable and Underrated Books for Software Engineers</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-most-valuable-and-underrated-books-for-software-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:06:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-most-valuable-and-underrated-books-for-software-engineers/</guid>
      <description>Every software engineers should read those 4 books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
