<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>complexity on Laurent Parenteau</title>
    <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/complexity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in complexity on Laurent Parenteau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:49:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laurentparenteau.com/tags/complexity/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplification: The Key to Scaling Engineering in Fast-Growing Startups</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:49:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/simplification-the-key-to-scaling-engineering-in-fast-growing-startups/</guid>
      <description>In startups, rapid growth is the holy grail. Founders dream of the day their company takes off, experiencing exponential user growth, revenue, and market share. However, this dream scenario comes with its own set of challenges, particularly for engineering teams. Recently, I had an enlightening conversation with the head of engineering at a young startup experiencing this very situation. Their story is a valuable lesson for engineering leaders facing similar challenges in fast-growing environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Growth: Myth, Reality, and Strategic Considerations</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:37:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/exponential-growth-myth-reality-and-strategic-considerations/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard the Indian story of the man who asked for his reward to be 1 grain of wheat placed on the 1st square of a chessboard and doubling the number of grains on each subsequent square. While there are only 64 squares, you&amp;rsquo;d need 2,000 times the world&amp;rsquo;s wheat production to provide that reward. This famous story shows our lack of intuition about exponential growth and its power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Success and Failure: A Rational Approach</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/decoding-success-and-failure-a-rational-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 07:08:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/decoding-success-and-failure-a-rational-approach/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving world of software engineering, we are often presented with the challenge of assessing successes and failures. When evaluating our own performance, we frequently attribute our successes to our skills and our failures to bad luck. However, when it comes to evaluating the results of our competitors, the tendency is quite the opposite: we tend to ascribe their failures to a lack of skill and their successes to sheer luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the Grey: A Probabilistic Approach to Engineering Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/embracing-the-grey-a-probabilistic-approach-to-engineering-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 07:10:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/embracing-the-grey-a-probabilistic-approach-to-engineering-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen my fair share of successes and failures in the world of technology. Throughout the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across various approaches to decision-making and problem-solving, each with its own set of principles and methodologies. However, one idea that recently struck a chord with me is the concept of &amp;ldquo;thinking in bets&amp;rdquo; as outlined by Annie Duke in her book of the same name.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore how this concept can revolutionize the way we make decisions in the field of software engineering and challenge the conventional wisdom that often prevails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Simplicity: Why Complex Solutions Aren&#39;t Always Better</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:17:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/the-power-of-simplicity-why-complex-solutions-aren-t-always-better/</guid>
      <description>In the world of software engineering, complexity often takes center stage. We celebrate intricate algorithms, sprawling architectures, and convoluted code as signs of expertise. But what if I told you that complexity isn&amp;rsquo;t always the answer? In fact, more often than not, simpler solutions are not only easier to understand and maintain but also more effective in solving real-world problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand why complexity is alluring. Complex code and systems can make us feel like we&amp;rsquo;re tackling profound problems, and they can impress colleagues and peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking the Right Tool for a Remote Engineering Team</title>
      <link>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/picking-the-right-tool-for-a-remote-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 20:34:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentparenteau.com/posts/picking-the-right-tool-for-a-remote-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>The Problem
When you have a remote engineering team, the tools you use are really important since you can’t use an office as a band-aid. We had some issues with our project management tools, where some information didn’t reach the relevant people. We needed to fix that to improve our productivity.
Actions Taken
My first action was to reach out to everyone involved and get more feedback on our current software engineering process, what’s working well and what isn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
